Ji Yong Cho

106 Village Circle, Ithaca, NY 14850

I research user engagement in online platforms and technologies, including identifying factors associated with engagement, devising interventions to increase engagement, and measuring the impact of the interventions. I primarily take a quantitative approach by applying data science and machine learning techniques, but I also conduct qualitative studies to gain deeper insights into target users during software development.

EDUCATION

Cornell University Ph.D. in Information Science	Ithaca, NY Aug. 2018 – Aug. 2024 (expected)
University of Pennsylvania (UPenn) M.C.I.T in Computer Information and Technology M.S.Ed. in Interdisciplinary Studies in Human Development	Philadelphia, PA 2018 2016
Ewha Womans University B.B.A in Psychology, Business Administration	Seoul, South Korea, 2014 2014

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Research scientist (@Applied Machine Learning Lab)

LG AI Research, April 2023 - June 2024

Email: jc3374@cornell.edu

Website: https://jiyongcho.github.io/

LLMs' Performance Metrics in Expert Knowledge Domains

- Research the consistency of LLM auto-evaluation in long-form writing and question answering (QA)
- Research diverging and converging knowledge in LLMs' QA (a manuscript under review)
- Developed a measure for inspiration in the use of LLMs in research ideation (a manuscript under review)

Human-Centered Evaluation of LLMs

- Identified use cases for LLM-powered tools for knowledge workers
- Administered individual interviews and focus group studies with 130+ researchers and engineers in AI/ML area
- Developed an evaluation taxonomy for LLMs' QA capabilities, driven by theoretical work in Social Science and reflecting perspectives from foundational ML researchers
- Designed and ran end-to-end human evaluations on LLMs for 3 cycles of model development
- Analyzed, visualized, and wrote up end-to-end human evaluations for diverse stakeholders

Data Pipelines for LLM development

- Developed a data collection tool for an LLM; API development and wireframe design as a part of a team
- Administered a series of data collection, working with external research labs
- Manage database and curate training/test data for each module in an LLM
- Share insights with the engineering team for improving models from end-users perspectives

Knowledge Sharing Tool Development

- Design and develop an LLM-powered knowledge-sharing tool for researchers
- Write APIs, set up databases, design wireframes
- Test a Proof of Concept by running prototype studies
- Collaborate with external labs in NLP, human-computer interaction, and industrial design for research projects
- Research useful interaction designs in LLM-powered systems
- Prepare manuscripts (under review) and give a demonstration (e.g., NeurIPS 2023)

SKILLS

- Languages: proficient: Python, R; intermediate: SQL, JavaScript; basic: C/C++, Java, Go
- Development: FastAPI, MongoDB, MySQL, Docker, Google Cloud Computing
- Data Analytics: Log data mining, Causal inference, Online-based experiments, Sampling, Data imputation, Survey & measure development, Python libraries (scikit-learn, etc.), Qualtrics
- UX/Intervention Studies: Quantitative research (regression, ANOVA, etc.), Qualitative research (Interviews, focus group studies, Co-design workshops, Persona development/ User scenarios, Figma, Content analysis)

Online Course Learner Profiles

Cornell University, Jan 2021 - May 2023

- Perform data mining on users' large behavioral time stamp data (92GB), collected from 150+ Harvard EdX Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs) for 3+ years.
- Find behavioral patterns using AI/ML techniques and connect them with 1.5 billion user surveys (e.g., study plans).

Help-seeking in College Subreddits

Cornell University, Jan 2020 - Dec 2021

- Investigated topics users shared in online communities (Reddit).
- Identified factors associated with users' active participation in online communities.
- Applied NLP techniques and fitted predictive modeling with 3-year Reddit archived data (100K+ posts) and U.S. Department of Education data (1K+ colleges)

Student Engagement in Corde.org

Cornell University, Jan 2019 - Dec 2020

- Examined changes in students' engagement with an online learning platform over time.
- Identified important factors that affect students' continuous use of the platform and their learning outcomes.
- Analyzed a year-long trace data of 83K+ students from 11K+ class sections, combined with three-time-point user surveys, imputing missing data, and fitting hierarchical linear models.

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

CoachEra (Mobile application)

Cornell University, Jan 2020 - Dec 2022

- Designed and developed a chatbot-based app to help learners make weekly study plans, utilizing open-sourced code.
- Led a team of 5+ members (graphic/UX/UI designers, front/back-end engineers.
- Released the app in iOS & Android to serve 200+ students simultaneously.

Delivery Ghost (Browser web game)

Cornell University, Jan 2018 - Dec 2020

- Designed and developed a game that teaches Chinese in an immersive way, with minimal English translation.
- Led a team of 5+ members, developers & graphic designers.
- Designed game mechanics, implemented with Phaser engine (JavaScript); connected with MySQL database; conducted user studies.
- The game was played by 500+ learners, demonstrating a significant improvement in vocabulary acquisition.

Music Play E-Textile Learning Kit (Physical computing kit)

UPenn, 2018

- Developed educational artifacts to teach programming concepts, using circuits and Arduino in C++.
- Worked with learning scientists, instructors, and target students
- The kit was used for a CS summer bootcamp for 50+ high school students

OTHER EXPERIENCES

- Teaching: Taught weekly sessions, coached students for semester-long projects, and provided feedback on assignments and projects for 6 courses (50 300 students in class), including introductory programming (Java & Python), web development/app prototyping, and learning analytics. Received Cornell Information Science Outstanding TA Award Year 2018-9 for excellence in teaching user-centered web development and guiding students' projects.
- Research: Led 5+ collaborative research projects using various methods, including data mining, regression fitting, and predictive modeling. Assisted 5+ collaborators in different fields (e.g., Marketing, communication, education, psychology, design, natural language processing). Published research papers at CHI, L@S, etc.. (publications).
- Mentoring: Mentored 20+ undergraduate students in research projects (2018-2023); Served as a mentor for first-year PhD students in Information Science (2019-2023)

Graduate-Level Technical Courses Taken

- Computer Science: Software engineering, Artificial intelligence, Big data analytics, Computer system programming, Operating system design and implementation, Networked system, Implementation of cloud networks
- Statistics: Regression and analysis of variance, Causal reference, Linear models with matrices, Learning analytics
- UX/UI research: Research design and analysis, Computational methods for information science research, Social research design and methods, Human-computer interaction studio